(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T00:58:20.217359",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ファイ！ギミー！キミに問いかけたい
Phi! Gimme! I want to ask you,
そのアツイ情熱の進化
The evolution of that burning passion.
待って 違和感の理由
Wait, the reason for this unease...
恋じゃ まだ 弱い な
It's still too weak to be love.
百通りの好きが飽和しても
Even if a hundred ways of liking are saturated,
なりたいのはオンリーワン
What I want to be is your only one.
思わず成長していく この髪は卒業？
Growing up before I knew it, is this hair graduation?
キミがちゃんと振り向いてくれたら きっとそれが完成形
If you properly turn to face me, surely that's complete.
理屈じゃないとかどこかで読んだコトバより
Rather than words read somewhere about it not being logic,
めいっぱい背伸びしたい はじめての挑戦かもね
I want to stretch as much as I can, maybe my first challenge!
ファイ！ギミー！キミに問いかけたい
Phi! Gimme! I want to ask you,
そのアツイ情熱の進化
The evolution of that burning passion.
そう キミが キミ である 存在 が 語る ミラクル
Yes, the existence of you being you tells a miracle.
ねぇ、もっと知りたい この胸 が 高鳴る 仕組み
Hey, I want to know more about how my heart beats fast.
もはや 恋 さえ 凌駕しちゃう アタラシイ 革命 の 予感
A premonition of a new revolution surpassing even love.
今日 も s.o.s 駆けつけて 来 て ね ヒーロー rescue！！
Today too, come running to my SOS, hero rescue!
ファイ！ギミー！キミに問いかけたい
Phi! Gimme! I want to ask you,
そのアツイ情熱の進化
The evolution of that burning passion.
そう キミが キミ である 存在 が 語る ミラクル
Yes, the existence of you being you tells a miracle.
ねぇ、もっと知りたい この胸 が 高鳴る 仕組み
Hey, I want to know more about how my heart beats fast.
もはや 恋 さえ 凌駕しちゃう アタラシイ 革命 の 予感
A premonition of a new revolution surpassing even love.
今日 も s.o.s 駆けつけて 来 て ね ヒーロー rescue！！
Today too, come running to my SOS, hero rescue!
why？キミに問い掛けたい そのアツい情熱のパラダイス
Why? I want to ask you, the paradise of that hot passion
もうキミがキミでなきゃ この星がピンチなんだよ
If you aren't you, this planet is in a pinch!
ねえ いつか言わせて トキメキが生み出すコトバ
Hey, let me say it someday, the words created by excitement
それを 愛ともリンクしちゃう オトナ未満
Linking that even with love, pre-adult
わたしの革命
My revolution
いつだって今が最高でしょ ready go!
Right now is always the best, ready go!
ねえどうですか 盛り上がってますか
Hey, how is it? Are you excited?
みんなも いっぱい歌いましょうからね
Everyone, let's sing a lot too!
ねえ教えて 聞かせて これからどうなるの
Hey, tell me, let me hear, what happens from now on?
これ以上ないくらい トキメキが
Excitement accelerating so much there's no more
加速しちゃうよ
It's accelerating!
目覚めてく 私たちだけのカタチ
Awakening, the shape that is only ours
tell me why キミに伝えたい そのアツい情熱のシンカ
Tell me why, I want to tell you, the evolution of that hot passion
そう キミがキミである 存在が語るミラクル
Yes, your very existence tells a miracle
ねえ もっと知りたい この胸が宝の仕組み
Hey, I want to know more, this chest is a treasure mechanism
もはや 恋さえ 凌駕しちゃう アタライサイ 革命の予感
Surpassing even love, a premonition of revolution
今日も SOS 駆けつけて来てね ヒーロー rescue!
Today too, come running to S.O.S., Hero rescue!
はい、ということで、はい、1曲目からテンションが上がっちゃいましたー！
Yes, with that, my tension went way up right from the first song!
ということで皆さんこんばんはー！白上フブキでございます。
So everyone, good evening! This is Shirakami Fubuki.
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy birthday!
テンション上がったー！
My tension went up!
えーどうですか今日ですね、あの、白上フブキ、お誕生日…
Um, how is it, today, um, Shirakami Fubuki, birthday...
お誕生日、お越しいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to my birthday!
いやもう本当に、ひとりぼっち、緊張する。
Man, really, all by myself, I'm so nervous.
実はひとりでこうやってね、あのYouTubeで、ソロライブやるのは初めてなので、もうめちゃめちゃ緊張してます、うわー！
Actually doing a solo live stream like this alone on YouTube for the first time, I'm super duper nervous, wow!
なんですけども、さ、早速、2曲目行いてみたいと思います！聞いてください、ワーネットムーン。
That being said, let's try going into the second song right away! Please listen, Garnet Moon.
髪にさした赤い薔薇は情熱の色
The red rose pinned in my hair is the color of passion
私を見た貴方まるでお熱いマタドール
You who looked at me are like a hot matador
きらびやかに舞い踊れば高鳴る胸
If I dance brilliantly, my chest beats high
二度と来ない刻の色を染めるエピソード
An episode coloring the hue of a time that will never come again
燃える想い奏でるギター
A guitar playing burning feelings
愛しさを紡ぐのでしょう
Spinning loveliness, isn't it?
旅人よ 傷あと痛むのなら 私の胸で眠りなさい
O traveler, if your scars and wounds ache, sleep upon my chest
慈しみながら 包んで あなただけ照らすのよ
Tenderly embracing you, illuminating only you
今宵の月のように
Like tonight's moon
夢を探す あなたは往く 荒野の果て
Searching for dreams, you go to the end of the wilderness
夢を見てる 私は今、孤独の海
Dreaming of dreams, I am now a sea of solitude
戻らない日々に 涙零して
Tears spill for the days you cannot return to
見上げた空は あかく あかく 燃える
The sky above burns crimson
自分の強さ弱さ 気づけたのなら 今
If you realize your own strength, weakness, then now
君王恐るるな
You, don't fear
心赴くまま 風を切り進む
Cut through the winds as your heart wills
その旅路を 暁が照らす
The dawn will shine upon your journey
集え
Gather
猛き腕 千里の瞳
The ferocious arm, the eyes that see a thousand leagues
天を羽ば行き行く脚 久遠の盾
The legs that run through the skies, the eternal shield
古の誓い 今果たして
Here, fulfill the ancient vow
夜よ明けてゆけ
O night, break
水面 落ちる 花一つ どこへ どこへ 流れ
A single blossom falls upon the water's surface, far away, far away it drifts
誰が知るか 君王の 心はまだ雲の中
Who knows the heart of the king, clouded yet
よぎる迷いを 貫くように
As if piercing a passing doubt
弓に矢つがえ とおく とおく 放つ
Nock your arrow to your bow, release it far, far away
朱の髪を なびかせて
Your crimson hair flutters
生きる事を 決めたのなら
You've decided you will live on
割れた爪も 傷跡も
Your torn nails and scars
明日への糧にして
Will become tomorrow's strength
君王忘るるな
You, don't forget
燃ゆる空の果てに いつか視た夢の
Your dream of seeing the burning end of the skies
その欠片が 目覚め 待つだろう
Those fragments will surely awaken, waiting
君王恐るるな
You, don't fear
心赴くまま 眼差しの炎
Following your heart, the flame in your gaze
絶たぬよう 君らしく進め
Advance true to yourself, never letting it fade
白き絆を交わせ
Exchange white bonds
青の夜に祈り捧げ
Offer your prayers to the azure night
緑の種を蒔いて
Sow seeds of green
黄金の実りを抱け
And embrace the golden fruit
旅人よ傷跡痛むのなら
Traveler, if your scars still hurt,
私の胸で眠りなさい
sleep upon my chest.
慈しみ知るほど潤う 月よ今日も輝く
The moon shines today as well, moistening as we learn compassion,
きらきら揺れながら
shimmering and swaying.
旅人よ今宵の月のように
Traveler, like tonight's moon,
叶わないかも
perhaps it won't come true,
晴れのち曇りて
with the clouds after clear skies,
雨が降るけど 一緒に帰ろう
it's going to rain, but let's go home together.
ドキドキドキしちゃってる
My heart is beating super fast,
こいつは全然気付かないな
And this guy isn't noticing at all!
本当はもっと話したいのに しつこいなんて思われてもな
Actually, I want to talk more with him, though it seems like I'm persistent,
授業中も上の空だし こんなの悔しいけれど仕方ないな
My head is in the clouds during class, it's so frustrating but I guess it can't be helped
恋空予報 叶わないかも
The love sky forecast might not come true,
晴れのち曇りで雨が降るでしょう
With the clouds after the clear skies, it's probably gonna rain
あいつの笑顔いつも見とれて
I'm always charmed by that guy's smile
私本気恋してる模様
Today, it looks like I'm in love
ほらほらもたもたしてると あっという間にあいつは帰るぞ
Hey look, if I slow down, that guy will go home in the blink of an eye!
今までずっと言えなかったけど 本当はづっと好きだったから
"I couldn't say it until now, but truly, I've always liked you!"
答えは待って！すぐに言わないで
"I'll wait for your answer! Don't say anything yet!"
耳をふさぎたくて ただ怖くて
I want to block my ears, I'm just so scared
恋空予報 叶えてお願い
The love sky forecast, please grant my wish
雨が降ってるけど 一緒に帰ろう
"It's raining, but let's go home together"
あいつのことは いつも思い出して
I'll always remember that guy's words
私明日も恋してる模様
Tomorrow too, it looks like I'm in love
遠くかかる虹 ふわり混ざる夕日
A rainbow spanning far and wide, gently blending into the setting sun
傘をたたんで 手をつないだ幸せもの
I folded my umbrella and held your hand, and I'm so happy
今日も恋空予報 これからもきっと
The love sky forecast, today again, surely from here on
晴れのち曇りで雨も降るでしょう
With the clouds after the clear skies, it's gonna rain too
あいつの笑顔いつも見とれて
I'm always charmed by his smile
私本気恋してる模様
Today, it looks like I'm in love
夢をみた 儚い夏の日に出逢う
I had a dream of meeting you on a fleeting summer day.
思い出すのが怖くて 後ろ向いて目を閉じれば
Afraid to remember, if I turn back and close my eyes,
忘れられるような気がした
it felt like I could forget it all.
あれから途切れた世界に いつまでもいたかったな
Ever since, in that broken world, I wanted to stay forever.
繰り返す日々に巻き付いた 後悔とぎこちない笑顔
Entangled in repeating days, regret and an awkward smile.
少し離れて眠るあしたに降る 雨の匂いが胸を締め付けて痛いよ
The scent of rain falling on tomorrow sleeping slightly apart squeezes my heart, it hurts.
触れていたくて繋いだ手は あしただけのものじゃないって
The hands we held because we wanted to touch weren't just for tomorrow,
知ってしまった
I've come to know that.
はい、ということで！ 2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
Yes, and with that, you've heard two songs in a row!
いやー めちゃめちゃ緊張した！
Man, I was so super nervous!
足震えてなかったですかね？
Weren't my legs shaking?
あー、多分、多分大丈夫だと思います！
Ah, well, I think it's probably fine!
それでね、ダーリンとかも、しょこみ、下野紘さんに
And you know, "Darling" and all... Shimono Hiro-san,
瞳さん！大好き！勝つね！
Hitomi-san, I love them! We won, right?
ま、これが主題歌になりました、ゲームも大好き！
Well, this became the theme song, and I love the game too!
ということで、いつかライブで歌ってやるぞという
So I've always had this feeling of wanting to sing it live someday,
気持ちでね、はい。心意気で歌いました。
with all my heart, yes. I sang it with all my spirit.
難しかったですね！
It was so hard!
そして恋空予報ですね。ま、白上の大好きなボカロ曲でもありまして
And then "Ren'ai Yohou". Well, it's one of my favorite Vocaloid songs,
いつかネ、なんか歌いたいな、歌ってみた動画とか出したいなと思ったんですけど
and I always thought I'd love to sing it someday or release a cover video,
こうやってね、ライブでやらせていただきました！
and now I finally got to perform it live like this!
でわでは、ここからはですね、コラボパートに移りたいと思います！
Now then, from here on, we'll move on to the collaboration part!
そういった、誰がゲストで来るでしょうか？
So, who could the guest be?
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
神のまにまに
As the gods will,
仰せのまにまに
as the heavens command,
誰だって地球を愛してる
everyone loves this Earth.
思い通りにいかないことだらけ どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
So many things don't go my way, I feel hopelessly self-loathing.
八百万の痛みや悲しみから逃げ込める場所を探している
I'm searching for a place to escape from countless pains and sorrows.
いっそ 岩の間に引き篭もって月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
I might as well hide in a rock crevice and sleep, ignoring moon and sun.
生まれてきたことの意味なんて知らない わからないよ
I don't know the meaning of being born, I don't understand it at all.
でも そんなふうに思えるってことは 君がもっともっと素敵になれる力があるって教えてるんだよ
But thinking that way shows you have the power to become even more wonderful.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのまにまに 誰だって地球を愛してる
That's right, as the gods will, as the heavens command, everyone loves this Earth.
飲みや歌えや ドンチャン騒ぎ たまにゃそんなのもいいね
Drink, sing, and carouse; once in a while, that's nice too.
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も なんだけんだ地球を愛してる
That's right, north and south, right and left, we all love the Earth in our own way.
泥まみれだけど 歩いていける まだまだ先は長いさ
Even though we're muddy, we can keep walking; we still have a long way to go.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのまにまに 誰だって地球を愛してる
That's right, as the gods will, as the heavens command, everyone loves this Earth.
飲みや歌えや ドンチャン騒ぎ たまにゃそんなのもいいね
Drink, sing, and carouse; once in a while, that's nice too.
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も なんだけんだ地球を愛してる
That's right, north and south, right and left, we all love the Earth in our own way.
泥まみれだけど 歩いていける まだまだ先は長いさ
Even though we're muddy, we can keep walking; we still have a long way to go.
ただ正しい人でいたいだけ きっと誰もがそれが合っているけど
I just want to be a righteous person; surely everyone wishes for that, but
八百万の心の醜さに苦しめられる毎日さ
every day we are tormented by the ugliness in millions of hearts.
僕が生まれてきたこと 奇跡と言えば聞こえいいけど
The fact that I was born—calling it a miracle sounds nice, but
それはきっと偶然に過ぎなくて やっぱり意味なんてないさ
it's surely nothing more than a coincidence, after all, it has no meaning.
でも 例えば君にいじめわるをする奴がいるなら
But for example, if there's someone teasing you,
それは君がとっても素敵な人だって教えてるんだよ
that's telling me you're such a wonderful person.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのまにまに 誰だって地球を愛してる
That's right, as the gods will, as the heavens command, everyone loves this Earth.
飲めや歌えや ドンチャン騒ぎ たまにゃそんなのもいいね
Drink, sing, and carouse; once in a while, that's nice too.
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も なんだけんだ地球を愛してる
That's right, north and south, right and left, we all love the Earth in our own way.
泥まみれだけど 歩いていける まだまだ先は長いさ
Even though we're muddy, we can keep walking; we still have a long way to go.
思い通りにいかないことだらけ
Things never go the way I want,
どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
I'm hopelessly self-loathing.
八百万の痛みや悲しみから
Seeking a place to escape
逃げ込める場所を探している
from countless pains and sorrows.
いっそ岩の間に引きこもって
I might as well hide away in a rocky crevice,
月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
and sleep, ignoring both the moon and sun.
生まれてきたことの意味なんて知らない 分かんないよ
I don't know the meaning of being born at all.
でも そんな風に思えるってこと それは
But the fact that you can feel that way,
君がもっともっと素敵になれる力があるって教えてるんだよ
shows you have the power to become even more wonderful.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに 誰だって地球を愛している
That's right, as God wills, as requested, everyone loves the earth!
飲めや歌えや どんちゃん騒ぎ たまにゃそんなのもいいね
Drink and sing, make a ruckus; once in a while, that's fine too!
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も なんかかんか地球を愛している
That's right, north and south, right and left, we all love the earth!
泥んこだけど歩いていける まだまだ先は長いさ
We can keep walking even covered in mud, we still have a long way to go!
ただ正しく人でありたいだけ きっと誰もがそう願っている
We just want to live righteously, surely everyone wishes for that,
八百万の心の醜さに苦しめられる毎日さ
tormented every day by the ugliness in countless hearts.
自分が生まれてきたこと 奇跡と言えば聞こえはいいけど
Saying our birth was a miracle sounds nice,
それはきっと偶然にすぎなくて やっぱり意味なんてないさ
but it's surely just coincidence, meaning nothing at all.
でも 例えば君にいじめをするやつがいるなら それは
But if there's someone bullying you out there,
君にとってとっても素敵な人だって教えてるんだよ
it shows that you are an exceptionally wonderful person.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに 誰だって地球を愛している
That's right, as God wills, as requested, everyone loves the earth!
僕が笑って君も笑えば 許せないことなんてないよ
If I smile and you smile too, there's nothing we can't forgive.
そうさ 男も女も恋しかるべき そんな風に地球は回ってる
That's right, men and women should fall in love; that's how the earth turns.
泥んこだけど歩いて行こう まだまだ先は長いさ
Let's keep walking even covered in mud, we still have a long way to go!
本当に大事なものは隠れているんだよ 大きな花を天まで届くくらいのラララ...
Truly precious things are hidden away, like big flowers reaching up to the heavens, la la la...
はーい！というわけで、みおとあやめちゃんでーす！
Yay! So, yep! It's Mio and Ayame!
イエーイ！
Yay!
今日誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
Happy birthday today! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！ありがとう、ふたりとも！いえーい！おめでたいね！
Thank you! Thank you both! Yay! Congratulations!
ということでね、ま、三人でね、なんかね、お祝いをうたったんだけども！
So yeah, we sang a celebratory song together!
そう！こないだもね、あやめちゃんのね、あの、誕生日の、そう、周年記念！
That's right! Recently was Ayame's birthday, well, anniversary!
そうそう周年記念！そう、周年記念！んで、踊ったので！
That's right, anniversary! And since she danced,
なんかね、三人で別の曲もやってみたいなということで、神のまにまにを踊らせていただきました！
we wanted to try another song together, so we performed "Kami no Manimani"!
イエーイ！イエーイ、ありがとうございます！
Yay! Yay, thank you so much!
わ、ふうさん、ね、初めでだったよね？ねえ、いや本当に！
Fubu-san, it was your first time, right? Yeah, truly!
いや、やっぱこういう曲を歌うのもね、まにまにはいいですね！
Singing a song like this is really nice!
そう、とんとことんとこ... ふふっ、ありがとうございました！
Yeah, tonto-kotonto... Haha, thank you very much!
今日ケーキ食べたのおきたまみは？ ケーキまだ食べてなーい！えー！？
Have you guys eaten cake yet, Okayu and Mio? We haven't eaten cake yet! What?!
え、じゃあこれ終わったらみんなで食べましょう！
Eh, then let's all eat it after this!
あ！でかいの食べたい！でかいの食べたい！
Ah! I want to eat a big one! I want a big one!
このあともね、まだあのコラボのメンバーいますので、それ終わったらみんなでケーキ食べて終わりましょう！
There are still collab members after this, so let's eat cake together and wrap up!
やだー！ありがとうございました！ということで、みおとあやちゃんでしたー！
No way! Thank you very much! So that was Mio and Ayaya!
ありがとう！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Congratulations! Thank you!
ニッポン笑顔百景
Nippon Egao Hyakkei
寿限無寿限無 五劫の擦り切れ
Jugemu Jugemu, Gokou no Surikire,
海砂利水魚の水行末 雲来末 風来末
Kajari Suigyo no Suigyomatsu, Unraimatsu, Furaimatsu,
食う寝る処に住む処
Kuu neru toko ni sumu toko,
やぶ小路のぶら小路
Yabukouji no burakouji,
パイポパイポパイポのシューリンガン
Paipo paipo paipo no Shuuringan,
シューリンガンのグーリンダイ
Shuuringan no Guurindai,
グーリンダイのポンポコピーのポンポコナの
Guurindai no Ponpokopi no Ponpokona no,
長久命の長助！
Choukyuumei no Chousuke!
ちょっとお時間いただきます
Pardon us for a moment,
ご静聴ください 整いましたー！
please listen closely, we're ready!
笑うことと掛けまして
Riddled with laughter,
お祭り野郎と解きます
we solve it as festival fellows!
その心は どちらも法被になるでしょう！
The punchline: both will end up happy!
お後がよろしいようで
Hope that suits you!
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, come on, let's laugh in times like these!
笑おう 泣いたら負けだ ヤケクソ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, crying means you lose, let's laugh recklessly!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも 乗り越えた アッパレ日本人
Through ups and downs, sweets and bitters, we're great Japanese!
笑おう どんな時でも ナニクソ笑いましょう
Let's laugh no matter what, laugh defiantly!
ひたむき笑いましょう 空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Let's laugh earnestly, laughing without reading the room!
笑顔 笑顔 笑う門には福来る
Smile, smile, fortune comes to the smiling gate!
え、皆さん、今日はようこそおいでいただきました！
Everyone, welcome today!
ここで一件！ネズミの娘が嫁に行ってすぐに帰ってきたんで
Here's a story! A rat's daughter got married and came right back home,
ネズミのお母さんが大怒って、あんなええ所へおまえ嫁いで誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？
and her mother got furious, asking who she was trying to avoid by coming back!
いや誰も嫌じゃないんですけどご隠居さんが優しいんで嫌なの！
But nobody was unkind; the master was just too nice, which is why she left!
よーい、これね！
Ready, right here!
でも猫又で声ですもの！
Because it's Nekomata's voice!
忙しさに身を任せて
Leaving it up to the hustle and bustle,
消えてゆくんだなんて べらめぇ
vanishing just like that? Nonsense!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても
Let's laugh, let's laugh, even if you can't,
笑うしかないでしょ
you have to laugh, right?
笑おう ソイヤソイヤ ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's laugh, soiya soiya, just keep laughing!
大いに悩んだ一歩さえクリアして
Clearing even the steps we agonized over,
現代日本人 笑おう
modern Japanese people, let's laugh!
未来へいこう グﾊﾊと笑いましょう
Let's head to the future, laughing 'guhaha'!
娘の可愛さとうとう切り捨てないで
Don't finally discard a daughter's cuteness!
しかめつらなんかけんな顔
Don't make a scowling face,
笑顔を見たいから
because I want to see your smile!
笑おう 笑おう さぁ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh,
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
especially in times like these!
笑おう ソイヤソイヤ
Let's laugh, soiya soiya,
泣いたって負けだ 焼けくそ笑いましょう
crying means losing, let's laugh in desperation!
払う煩悩 乗り越えた暴れ日本人 笑おう
Wild Japanese who've overcome earthly desires, let's laugh!
未来へいこう グﾊﾊと笑いましょう
Let's head to the future, laughing 'guhaha'!
ひたすら笑いましょう
Just keep laughing!
わはは わはは にょほほ にょほほ
Wahaha wahaha nyhoho nyhoho,
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
laugh without reading the room!
笑顔 笑顔 笑う角には福来たる
Smile, smile, fortune comes to merry homes!
Congrats Birthday FOX
おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
Congratulations! Thank you very much!
ゲーマーズに人が来ました！
Gamers has gathered!
がとゲーマーズお久しぶりでございます
It's been a while, Hololive Gamers.
ゲーマーズって知ってますか？
Do you know Hololive Gamers?
知ってるよ！
We know!
ホロライブゲーマーズは何期の間にあるでしょう？
Which generation is Hololive Gamers between?
正解は二期と三期のの間でした！
The correct answer was between the 2nd and 3rd!
コーネも10月1日がお誕生日でね
Korone's birthday is also on October 1st,
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
今日はふぶきちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！
Today is Fubuki-chan's birthday, happy birthday!
ありがとう！本当に集まってくれてありがとうね！
Thank you! Thank you so much for gathering!
一番最初さ、寝てたよね、めっちゃ
At the very first, you were sleeping, right?
こうして本当にねゲーマーズが集まって 本当によかったです
I'm so glad Hololive Gamers could gather like this.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということでゲーマーズでした！
And that was Hololive Gamers!
フィクサー
[Song: Fixer]
今日までの記憶の全部を消してしまう時まで眠れない
Until the time I erase all my memories up until today, I cannot sleep.
あしたから生きていく自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I want a substitute for myself to live starting tomorrow so badly.
今日までの記憶の 全部を消してしまう時まで
Until all memories up until today are erased,
眠れない
I cannot sleep.
あしたから生きていく 自分の身代わりが欲しくて 堪らない
I want a replacement for myself starting tomorrow, I can't take it.
大丈夫と言わせて
Let me say it'll be fine,
後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
could you please not make it your fault afterwards?
今更意味ないから 後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
It's pointless now, could you please not make it your fault afterwards?
出来ない約束を
Promises we can't keep...
とうとうと溢れる一言一言ばかりに 脳を奪われるくらい
Overflowing words, completely capturing my mind.
意味を成さない 何も出来ない 見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らさない
Making no sense, nothing I can do, can't see, want to escape, want to fly, want to stop, won't let me look away.
だから
So...
沈め 沈め 息継ぎできないほどまで
Sink, sink, until I can't breathe anymore,
飽きるまで
until I'm sick of it.
落とせ 落とせ 救い垂らす時まで
Drop it, drop it, until salvation is offered,
嘘臭い粒々を 喉から絞り出した悲鳴毎 噛み砕く
biting to pieces every grain of lies with the screams forced from my throat.
笑顔が苦手なばっかで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
Smiles were always my weak point, I'll just get through it with a familiar tone,
なりたくなかった
I didn't want it to become this way.
今日役立つ 眠たい眠たい理想で 救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by useful, sleepy, sleepy ideals.
一番目は「い」の口で言う 力強く 固く 痛く 噛み締めて
The first one is said with an "I" shape, forcefully, firmly, painfully, biting down.
死んでしまえ しまえ
Just die already, already!
この先も過去も知らず
Not knowing the future or the past.
嫌いなら壊せ 壊せ
If you don't like it, break it, break it,
どうせなら加害者になればいい
if it has to be, you might as well become the perpetrator.
食べ切れない薺も 何も生めない悲しみも 味気なくて吐き出す前に
Unedible grass, sorrows that bear nothing, before I vomit them out in disgust,
もう
just...
もう次を歌え
Sing the next song already!
どうせなら踊れ踊れ 灰色になり切る前に
If it has to be, dance and dance, before turning completely gray!
打ち鳴らせ 変われ変われ 眠り落ちる時まで
Strike, change, change, until you fall asleep!
どうせなら奪え奪え 飼い慣した嘘暴いて 煮凝る頭に過ぎた
If it has to be, plunder, plunder, breaking the fake peace before it sets in,
虚像を見ていた 自分を見ていた
I was seeing illusions, I was seeing myself.
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
戦場へ!前線へ!そして死の淵まで! 命捨てたその覚悟を示せ!
To the battlefield! To the frontlines! And to the depths of death! Show your resolution to throw away your lives!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
聴こえるだろう あの砲声が
Can you hear those sounds of artillery?
抵抗する蟷螂の声だ
It is the voice of resistance struggling.
踏み潰せ!踏み潰せ!
Trample them down! Trample them down!
諸君、我々の任務はなんだ
What is our mission, gentlemen?
殲滅だ! 一機残らずの殲滅だ!
Annihilation! Total annihilation!
為すべきことは唯一つ 地獄を創れ!
The only thing to do is to create hell!
何故炎の中進んで行くのか
Why must we advance into the sea of fire?
弾丸の雨に打たれに行くのか
Why must we be battered by the rain of bullets?
笑止千万!国のためだ!
A thousand laughs! It's for the country!
戦場へ!前線へ!そして死の淵まで! 命捨てたその覚悟を示せよ!
To the battlefield! To the frontlines! And to the depths of death! Show your resolution to throw away your lives!
忠誠を!順応を!そして其の魂を 全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ!
Give your loyalty! Give your obedience! And offer all your souls to achieve victory!
さあ此処に構築してみろ! 天に届く死体の山に!
Now, build up right here a mountain of corpses reaching to the heavens!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
どこに恐怖があると言うんだ 見ろ 血肉が花火の様だ
Where do they say terror lies? Look, flesh and blood are like fireworks.
撒き散らす 撒き散らす 千の傷痕 忘れちゃいけないさ
Scatter them, scatter them, don't forget the thousand scars!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Halt!
戦場へ!前線へ!そして死の淵まで!
To the battlefield! To the front lines! To the brink of death!
命捨てたその覚悟を示せ!
Show this commitment born from casting your life away!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Halt!
聴こえるだろう あの砲声が
Can you hear the roar of the ringing cannon?
抵抗する蛆の声だ
It's the voice of struggling maggots resisting.
踏み潰せ!踏み潰せ!
Crush them under foot! Crush them under foot!
諸君、我々の任務は何だ
Unit, what is our mission?
殲滅だ!
Annihilation!
一機残さずの殲滅だ!
Annihilate every last one of them!
為すべきことは唯一つ 地獄を創れ!
There is only one thing we must do: create hell!
何故炎の中進んで行くのか
Why do we march through flames?
弾丸の雨に打たれに行くのか
Are we going to be gunned down by a rain of bullets?
笑止千万!帝国の為だ!
Absurd! It's for the Fatherland!
戦場へ!前線へ!そして死の淵まで!
To the battlefield! To the front lines! To the brink of death!
命捨てたその覚悟を示せよ!
Show your commitment to casting away your life!
忠誠を!順従を!そして其の魂を
Your loyalty! Your obedience! And your soul!
全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ!
Give them all up and raise the war cry!
さあ此処に築いてみせろ!
Now come and build it right here:
天に届く死体の山に!
A mountain of dead men reaching the high heavens!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Halt!
どこに恐怖があると言うんだ
If you ask where fear lies,
見ろ 血肉が花火の様だ
look right down here, flesh and blood are like fireworks!
撒き散らす 撒き散らす 千の傷跡
Scatter them! Scatter them! A thousand scars!
忘れちゃいけないさ 炎の熱も
I haven't forgotten a thing: the heat of the fire,
零れた臓腑も 最後の呻きも 濁った瞳も
the spilled entrails, the final groans, the clouded eyes—
吁呼、それこそを求めるのだ!
Ah, that is precisely what I seek!
安寧も平穏も増して和解なんて 牙を捨てた飼い犬の所業
Tranquil peace and reconciliation? That's the behavior of pet dogs who've abandoned their fangs!
絶望と混乱を掛けた狂気の沙汰は 地獄よりも楽園の様だ
A mad game of despair and turmoil is more like paradise than hell!
その四肢は踊る為に 踊り狂う為 有るのだ!
Those four limbs of yours—they're made to dance, to dance around in wild ecstasy!
人間に価値など無い 価値無き者同士の争いに 命の徒花を咲かせてみせろ!
Humans have no value whatsoever! Make the fruitless flowers of your lives bloom in a struggle between worthless beings!
法律でも秩序でも狂った奴が創っている
Even law and order are created by madmen,
まさに笑劇 不条理だけの起承転結
a true farce, a sequence of pure absurdity!
戦場へ!前線へ!そして死の淵まで!
To the battlefield! To the front lines! To the brink of death!
命捨てたその覚悟を示せよ!
Show your commitment to casting away your life!
忠誠を!順従を!そして其の魂を
Your loyalty! Your obedience! And your soul!
全て捧げ勝鬨を上げよ!
Give them all up and raise the war cry!
さあ此処に築いてみせろ! 天に届く死体の山に!
Now come and build it right here: a mountain of dead men reaching the high heavens,
木霊する恨みさえ 掻き消す爆発音
drowning out even the echoes of hatred with the sound of explosions!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Halt!
ゴーゴー！レッツゴー！
Go Go! Let's Go!
新しい時代 進んでく 私たち
Moving forward into a new era, the three of us
「みんなで進も～！」
"Let's all move forward!"
朝まで騒ごう 夜更かしは悪くないよね？
Let's party until morning, staying up late isn't bad, right?
「悪くないよね？」
"It's not bad, right?"
世界揺振らせるくらい 強い絆の中で ハイになってgo！
Within a strong bond that shakes the world, get high and go!
尻尾振ってgo！
Wag your tail and go!
3, 2, 1… バカタレーション！
3, 2, 1... Bakataration!
楽しんじゃえ さあ デライト！
Have fun, come on, delight!
聞かせて よね ザッツライト！
Let me hear you say, that's right!
今夜もそう ノリを巻け テンションで
Tonight too, ride the hype and keep the tension high
私たちが ナンバーワン！
We are number one!
いつだって オンリーワン！
Always the only one!
これ まで も そう ここ から も
Up until now and from here on too,
ワクワクは続いてくよ！
the excitement will keep on going!
ゴーゴー！レッツゴー！
Go Go! Let's Go!
初めての扉 さあ、ドンドン開けていこう
Open up those brand new doors one after another!
「怖がらずに行こ～！」
"Let's go without fear!"
ついついやさぐれ でも一人じゃない…よね？
Sometimes we get cynical, but we aren't alone... right?
「一人じゃない…よね？」
"We aren't alone... right?"
迷ってもいいよ だって寄り道もイベントだし 前のめりgo！
It's okay to get lost, because detours are just events along the way, leaning forward, go!
助走づけgo！
Take a running start, go!
まだまだ… バカタレーション！
Still going... Bakataration!
駆け抜けてこう オールウェイズ！
Run right through it, always!
はしゃぎながら オールデイズ！
Have fun all days!
ノリノリで海苔で巻け 大混乱
Get into the groove and roll it in seaweed, total chaos!
地球は広い けど
The earth is wide,
まるっと1周
a full 1-lap around,
シアワセで侵略 出来そう
looks like we can invade it with happiness!
ドタバタは続いてくよ！
The slapstick adventure continues!
遊び足りない日は もう少し一緒に みんなでときめこう 無敵な友情
On days when we haven't played enough, let's stay together a bit longer and get excited together in invincible friendship!
未来へと 振りかざして さあ、進め↑バカタレーション
Wielding it toward the future, now, advance↑ Bakataration!
楽しんじゃえ さあ デライト！
Have fun, come on, delight!
聞かせて よね ザッツライト！
Let me hear you say, that's right!
今夜もそう ノリを巻け テンションで
Tonight too, ride the hype and keep the tension high!
私たちが ナンバーワン！
We are number one!
いつだって オンリーワン！
Always the only one!
これ まで も そう ここ から も
Up until now and from here on too,
ワクワクは続いてくよ！レディゴー！
the excitement will keep on going! Ready go!
ゴーゴー！レッツゴー！
Go Go! Let's Go!
(ゴーー！) (レッツゴー！)
Let's go! Let's go!
新しい時代 進んでく 私たち
Heading forward into a new era, us girls!
(ゴーー！)
Let's go!
「みんなで進もー！」
"Let's all move forward!"
朝まで騒がそう 夜更かしは悪くないよね？
Let's party until morning, staying up late is fine, right?
(ゴーー！)
Let's go!
「悪くないよね？」
"It's fine, right?"
世界揺るがせるくらい 強い絆の中で
Within bonds strong enough to shake the world,
ハイになって go！
getting hyped, go!
(oh yeah！)
(Oh yeah!)
尻尾振って go！
Wagging our tails, go!
(oh yeah！)
(Oh yeah!)
3, 2, 1… バカタレレーション！
3, 2, 1... Bakatarention!
楽しんじゃえ さあディライト！
Enjoy it now, delight!
(delight！)
(Delight!)
聞かせてよねザッツライト！
Let me hear it, that's right!
(that's right！)
(That's right!)
今夜もそう ノリを巻け テンションで (yeah yeah)
Tonight too, let loose and stay hyped with tension (Yeah yeah)
私たちが ナンバーワン！
We are number one!
(ワン！)
(One!)
いつだって オンリーワン！
Always be the only one!
(ワン！)
(One!)
これまでも そう ここからも (ずっと)
From here on out, just like before and always (Forever)
ワクワクは 続いてくよ！
The excitement will keep going!
(ゴーー！) (レッツゴー！)
Let's go! Let's go!
初めての扉さぁ、ドンドン開けていこう (ゴーー！)
Opening the first door together with a bang! (Let's go!)
「怖がらず行こ～！」
"Let's go without fear!"
ついつい躓きそう でも一人じゃない…よね？ (ゴーー！)
Fumbling and stumbling around, but we're not alone... right? (Let's go!)
「一人じゃない…よね？」
"You're not alone... right?"
迷ってもいいよ だって寄り道もイベントだし
It's okay to get lost, detours are events too, after all!
前のめり go！
Going forward, go!
(oh yeah！)
(Oh yeah!)
助走つけ go！
Running headfirst, go!
(oh yeah！)
(Oh yeah!)
まだまだ… バカタレレーション！
Not yet... Bakatarention!
(イェーーーーーイー！！！)
(Yeaaaaaah!)
駆け抜けてこい オールウェイズ！ (always！)
Running through it all, always! (Always!)
はしゃぎながら オールデイズ！ (all days！)
Smiling all the way, all days! (All days!)
たーだ！
Ta-da!
ということで、突然で皆さんびっくりしたと思いますけども、
So, everyone might be surprised, but guess what?
なんと、この度バカタレのオリジナル楽曲ができましたー！
This time, Bakatarention got an original song!
わーい！
Yay!
やったー！
Yay! We did it!
ふぶちゃんのお誕生日プレゼントってこと？
Is this Fubuki's birthday present?
えっ、そういうことなの、これって。
Yeah, that's what this is!
そういことさ。
That's right!
そういことだったの！
That's what it was!
いや、誕生日にすまんね。
Man, thank you for the birthday gift!
いやあ、嬉しいよ。
I'm so happy!
でもこっそり準備してたじゃないか、ね？
We secretly prepared it, you know?
一緒にね、みんなでね。
Together, all of us.
まあまあまあまあ！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
ということで、猫・犬・羊で「進め↑BAKATARATION」というね、はい、オリジナルを、はい作ってみんなで歌っていただきました！
So, as cat-dog-sheep, we made "Susume Bakatarention"!
わーい！
Yay!
みんなバラバラの方向を向いているが！
We were facing all different directions though!
あつい！あつい！
Hot! It's hot!
あつい！バカタレ！
Hot, Bakatarention!
こちらの楽曲ですね、まあMVとかね、まあ発売とかはね、もちろん、もちろん！
As for this original song, like MV and release and stuff...
もちろんあるんですけども、今ね、YAGOOさんたちと相談しながら制作中でございますので！
Well, we're still discussing it with Yagoo,
はい、聞きたい方はぜひともまたこのね、ライブをアーカイブを見直していただいて、
So if you want to hear it more, please rewatch the live archive...
聞いて笑ってね、いつかはライブでやるぞ！
Laugh and smile, and one day sing it at a live concert!
おー！
Ooh!
いつかはね、リアルなバカタレライブでこの歌を歌いたいと思います、また！
Someday we want to sing this song at a real live concert again!
まだまだ、バカタレが話せません！
Still, still, Bakatarention cannot stop talking!
ということで皆さんありがとうございました！バカタレれどんでした！
So everyone, thank you so much, we were Bakatarention!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
この胸に あの日君が蒔いた
That day, you planted in this chest
小さな涙の種
a small seed of tears.
いつか大きな笑顔の花 咲かせるその日まで
Until the day it blooms into a big flower of smiles,
めまぐるしい 毎日の中でも
amidst these dazzling days,
時々不意に巻き戻してる
I sometimes unthinkingly rewind.
めまぐるしい毎日のなかでも時々不意に巻き戻してる
Even in the bustling everyday life, I sometimes unthinkingly rewind to the past.
あの先もずっと君といられたら
If I could always be with you from then on,
もしもの未来
a possible future...
どこにもいない姿を
Even if you're nowhere to be seen,
どこにいても感じたまま
I still feel you wherever I am.
今日も同じ空の下で
Today too, under the same sky,
明日へと向かうよ
I'm heading towards tomorrow.
繰り返す言葉はまるで心を溶かすように
These repeating words feel as though they are melting my heart,
僕に今語りかけるんだ
speaking to me now
愛しいその声で
with that beloved voice.
この胸に あの日君が蒔いた
That day, you planted in this chest
小さな涙の種
a small seed of tears.
いつか大きな笑顔の花 咲かせるその日まで
Until the day it blooms into a big flower of smiles,
ここにいるから
I'll be right here.
たぶん特別なことではなくて
It's not about anything particularly special,
やがて誰もがその意味を知る
soon everyone will know what it means.
赤く燃え尽きる雲の切れ間には
Through a break in the burning crimson clouds,
星が瞬く
stars are twinkling.
その瞳は今どこで
Where are your eyes now,
どんな景色を見ているの？
and what kind of scenery are they seeing?
君が好きだった季節が また巡ってくるよ
The season that you loved is rolling around again.
抱きしめた君の欠片たちは 何も変わらないまま
The fragments of you that I hold close haven't changed at all.
抱きしめた 君の欠片たちは
The fragments of you that I held close
何も変わらないまま
remain completely unchanged,
何度でも語りかけるんだ
and I'll talk to them over and over again
愛しいその声で
with that beloved voice of yours.
忘れない あの日君が蒔いた 小さな涙の種
I won't forget that small seed of tears you sowed that day—
いつか大きな笑顔の花 咲かせるその日まで
until the day it blooms into a great flower of smiles.
ここにいるから
Because I'm right here.
朝も昼も夜も 見つけながら 迷いながら
Morning, noon, and night, searching and hesitating,
僕らは約束の場所へ急ぐ
we hurry to our promised place.
繰り返す言葉は
The repeating words
すっかり心をとかすように 僕に今語りかけるんだ
speak to me now as if melting my heart,
愛しいその声で
with that beloved voice of yours.
この胸に あの日君が蒔いた 小さな涙の種
That small seed of tears you sowed in this chest of mine that day—
やっと大きな笑顔の花 咲かせたんだ
finally bloomed into a great flower of smiles.
きっといつまでも
I'm sure, forever and ever,
ここにいるから
because I'm right here.
逃げたり諦めることは 誰でも
Anyone can run away or give up in an instant,
一瞬あればできるから 歩き続けよう
so just keep on walking!
君にしかできないことがある
There is something only you can do.
青い星に 光が失せぬように
So that this blue star doesn't lose its light,
つかめ! 描いた夢を
Seize the dream you drew!
まもれ! 大事な友を
Protect your precious friends!
たくましい自分になれるさ
You can become a stronger self!
知らないパワーが宿る ハートに火がついたら
When an unknown power dwells and your heart catches fire,
どんな願いも嘘じゃない きっとかなうから
any wish isn't a lie, it will surely come true...
show me your brave heart
晴れの日ばかりじゃないから たまには冷たい雨も降るけれど
It's not always sunny days, so sometimes cold rain falls too,
傘ひろげよう 生き方に地図なんかないけれど
but let's open our umbrellas—there's no map for how to live,
だから自由 どこへだって行ける、君も
that's why we're free, you can go anywhere too.
はしれ! 風より速く メザせ! 空より遠く
Run faster than the wind! Aim farther than the sky!
新しい自分に逢えるさ
You can meet a new self!
知らない勇気が眠る ハートに気がついたら
When you realize the unknown courage sleeping in your heart,
胸の中のどしゃ降りも きっと止むから
the downpour in your chest will surely stop...
show me your brave heart
逃げたりあきらめるコトは 誰も
If anyone can give up and run
一瞬あればできるから 歩き続けよう
for even a second, just keep on walking.
君にしかできないことがある
There's something only you can do,
青い星に
so that this blue planet
光が失わぬように
doesn't lose its light.
つかめる！描いた夢を
Seize the dreams you drew!
まもれる！大事な友を
Protect your precious friends!
たくましい自分になれるさ
You can become stronger.
知らないパワーが宿る ハートに火がついたら
Unknown power dwells in your heart, when its fire is lit.
どんな願いも 嘘 じゃない
Any wish, it's not a lie,
きっと 叶う から
it will surely be granted.
show me your brave heart
皆さん、今日はありがとうね！
Everyone, thank you so much today!
ありがとうだよー！
Thank you so much!
はい、ということで2曲続けて聴いていただきました。本日はありがとうございましたー！
So, you've listened to two songs in a row. Thank you very much today!
涙のね、笑顔の花はですね、一昨年のライブの時は青空デイズを歌っていただいたんですけども
For "Namida no Tegami" / "Egao no Hana", during the 1st-gen live we had "Aozora Days" sung,
今回はブレイブハートということで皆さん進化しましたか？大丈夫ですか？
but this time it's "brave heart"—everyone, have you evolved? Are you alright?
では次で最後の曲なんですけども、ここでお知らせです！
Now, for the final song, and here is an announcement!
なんとなんと只今開催中の富士急ハイランドさんにて、10月5日今日から10日までの期間限定で白上の限定ボイスが聴けちゃいます！
Starting today, October 5th until the 10th at Fuji-Q Highland, you can listen to Shirakami's limited voice lines!
そしてなんとメリーゴーランドも白上のテーマファンファーレが流れちゃいますのでぜひ皆さん聴いてくださいおねがいします！
And what's more, Shirakami's theme fanfare will be playing on the merry-go-round too, so please go listen to it!
そしてもう1個なんとなんと明日！明日はですね白上のお誕生日コラボということでライブ2Dの...
And another thing—tomorrow! Tomorrow is Shirakami's birthday collaboration, so Live2D...
皆さん、最後の曲「Say! ファンファーレ！」行きますよー！
Everyone, for our final song, "Say! Fanfare!", let's go!
おっと！せーの！いぇーい！
Ready, set, yay!
はい！はい！おっ！ここ！うーーっ！
Hai! Hai! Woo! Here! Woo!
せーの！ are you ready!?
Ready? Are you ready?!
ほーっとひと息 お茶ですよ
Take a breath, it's tea time.
いつもの場所から 元気にせーのでご挨拶
Greeting you cheerfully from our usual place!
おっこんこんでーまーすーっ!
Hello-con-con-everyone!
始めましょう!
Let's begin!
おしゃべりをして ゲームと過ごす そんな毎日が 愛しくて
Chatting and playing games, loving every single day.
あれもこれも 手を出したくなりがちです
I tend to want to try everything out.
歌とかステージは まだまだ恥ずかしい けど
Singing and stages are still a bit embarrassing, but
支え合って ほら 届けますよ この声を
Supporting each other, I'll deliver this voice to you!
say!
ほらその顔上げて みんなで手を取れば
Raise your face and take each other's hands,
まだまだ道の途中 世界を超えよう
we're still on the way, let's cross the world!
ほらお仕事も 止まらない全力ですから!
Because our push-work never stops, giving it our all!
夢を書きかえてら 追いかけ続けよう ともに 繋ぐ ファンファーレ
Rewrite our dreams and keep chasing them, a fanfare connecting us together!
ほーっとひと息 お茶ですよ
Take a deep breath and have some tea!
黒い あのコには内緒にして欲しいです
Keep it a secret from that black one!
仲間のお力と お友達のみなさんと
With the strength of comrades and all of our friends,
叶えたい想いは 言葉にして 一つ一つ
turn every cherished wish into words, one by one!
Say! ほらその手を上げて
Say! Raise your hands up high,
みんなで輪になれ ば
and let's all form a circle together!
Dive! まだまだ成長途中 世界を越えよう
Dive! We're still growing, let's cross the world!
Say! ほら 明るく元気な 心が取り柄ですから
Say! Let's keep that bright and cheerful spirit!
へこみがちな時も 輝き続けよう
Even on down days, let's keep shining on,
共に繋ぐ アンコール!
connecting together in an encore!
Say! ほらその手を上げて
Say! Raise your hands up high,
みんなで手を取れば
and let's all take each other's hands!
Dive! これから夢の先へ
Dive! Head toward the end of our dreams!
Say! ほら 推しお仕事も 止まらない全力ですから!
Say! Oshi work is a non-stop, all-out effort!
何もかもが新しくって
When everything feels brand new,
右も左もわからない時も
and you don't know left from right,
頑張れたのは 一人じゃないからね
remember you weren't the only one trying hard.
一つ一つ応援が 後押しになって
Every single piece of support pushes me forward,
一歩ずつでも 私は自分らしく 磨いていくfuture
so I'll forge my own future, step by step!
答えも イメージも まだまだ手探りしても
Even as answers and images are still hard to find,
響き合って ほら 世界は今 色めいて
listen, the world is now coming alive in color!
Say! さあその顔上げて
Say! Raise your hands up high,
みんなで手を取れば
and let's all take each other's hands!
Dive! これから夢の先へ
Dive! Head toward the end of our dreams!
Say! ほら 推しお仕事も 止まらない全力ですから!
Say! Oshi work is a non-stop, all-out effort!
何もかもが新しくって
When everything feels brand new,
右も左もわからない時も
and you don't know left from right,
頑張れたのは 一人じゃないからね
remember you weren't the only one trying hard.
一つ一つ応援が 後押しになって
Every single piece of support pushes me forward,
一歩ずつでも 私は自分らしく 磨いていくfuture
so I'll forge my own future, step by step!
皆さん今日は 本当にありがとうございました!
Thank you all so much for today!
みんな お気に入りだよ!
Everyone loves you so much!